A Guide to the Society of Friends. Richmond Monthly Meeting records, 1975-2008
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Society of Friends. Richmond Monthly Meeting records, 1975-2008
The Library of Virginia
43869
1.25 cu. ft. (5 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Betsy Brinson, July 2008.
Biographical Information
In 1795, a Richmond Indulged Meeting was organized under the care of the White Oak Swamp Monthly Meeting. When the Weyanoke Monthly Meeting (formerly known as the White Oak Swamp Monthly Meeting) was disbanded in 1841, its members joined the Richmond Particular or Preparative Meeting, which then became part of the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting. In 1844, the Richmond Meeting was suspended under an agreement that the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting would meet occasionally in Richmond. By 1854, the Monthly Meeting was only meeting in Richmond. In 1875, the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting officially changed its name to the Richmond Monthly Meeting. The Richmond Monthly Meeting is part of the Baltimore Yearly Meeting.
Scope and Content
Records, 1975-2008, of the Richmond Friends Meeting, including clippings, financial ledgers, membership directories, newsletters, and publications. Includes an almost complete run of the newsletter, Among Friends (earlier called Between Friends), from 1976-2007. Also includes copies of the magazine, Friends Journal, 2005-2007, and newsletters from the Charlottesville and Washington Friends Meeting and Baltimore Yearly Meeting. Included are financial ledgers, 1943-1987, containing budgets, treasurer's reports, expenses, and incomes.
Contents List
- Clippings and scrapbook, 1977-1987. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Directories, 1976-1979. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Directories, 1980-1989. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Directories, 1990-1999. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Directories, 2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1985. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1986. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2002. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2003. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2004. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, Among Friends, 2008. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Newsletters, Friends Journal, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Newsletters, Friends Journal, 2006 January-June. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, Friends Journal, 2006 July-December. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, Friends Journal, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, other Quakers, 2006-2007. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Programs, Friends General Conference, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Publications, Quaker Action and Quaker Life, 2005-2007. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Publications, Quaker Books, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Publications, Quaker History, 2005 Fall. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Publications, Miscellaneous, 2004-2007. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Financial ledgers, 1943-1973. (Box 5)
- Financial ledgers, 1974-1977. (Box 5)
- Financial ledgers, 1978-1982. (Box 5)
- Financial ledgers, 1983-1987. (Box 5)